Contact

this.is.tim.dehof@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-dehof (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Matlab

Labview

Microsoft Office

Certifications

Six Sigma Yellow Belt

Engineer-In-Training / Fundementals of Engineering

Timothy Dehof

"Passionate Software Engineer | Devoted People Person | Anime Enthusiast"

Jacksonville

Summary

My name is Timothy Tyler Dehof. In 2011, I graduated from the University of North Florida with a Bachelor of Science degree in Mechanical engineering. Even though I have a Mechanical Engineering degree and seven years of engineering work experience, Tech has always been an interest to me and my new professional career focus. This year I took the plunge and attended a rigorous BootCamp and made a career change where I developed applications for the web.

I believe my years of mechanical engineering experience, combined with what I have learned about software development, is something I think I will be a great benefit to offer to a company.

Experience

Fullstack Academy

Student

February 2022 - Present (4 months)

- built web applications that focused on full-stack development
- worked on teams with emphasis on paired programming in an agile environment

Polyhistor International, Inc. Mechanical Design Engineer 2014 - January 2022 (8 years)

Jacksonville, Florida Area

- -Familiar with running a CNC milling machine Haas Super Mini Mill
- -Responsible for the operations and maintenance of an FDM 3D Printing machine Fortus 400mc
- -Responsible for the operations and maintenance of an SLA 3D Printing machine Formlabs Form 3
- -Responsible for the operations and maintenance of a laser cutting machine BossLaser LS-3650

-Responsible for the operations and maintenance of a fiber marking machine - BossLaser FM20

Snelling Staffing Services
Contracted Mechanical Engineering Technician
March 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 11 months)
Jacksonville, Florida Area

Assignments included:

Polyhistor International

- Produced manuals for Projects and machines to improve the projects' assembly process
- Assisted in the assembly of prototypes and products using tools to meet the customer specifications
- Assisted in the operations of Rapid Prototype Machine Objet Eden 260v
- Assisted in the assembly of wire harness to customer specifications
- Responsible for the operations of the automatic wire cutting machine

University of North Florida Mechanical engineering student January 2009 - December 2011 (3 years)

coursework electives: Robotics Engineering, Experimential learning in the Community (six sigma certification), and HVAC Systems.

Food Lion

Grocery clerk/Stocker January 2001 - February 2008 (7 years 2 months)

Ordered for the frozen foods Department

Assisted in the back stock organization of the grocery and frozen food sections to reduce wasted time

Assisted in unloading the grocery and frozen food trucks and prepared them for stocking the next day

Education

Fullstack Academy

· (February 2022 - May 2022)

University of North Florida

Bachelors of science, Mechanical Engineering · (2009 - 2011)

Florida State College of Jacksonville
Associate of Arts, Mechanical Engineering · (2006 - 2009)